Guido Santillán

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER · MECHATRONICS ENGINEER

Quito, Ecuador

☐ (+593) 987473691 | ☑ guidosantillan01@gmail.com | ※ www.guidosantillan.com |

guidosantillan01 | in guido92

"Be the change you want to see in the world."



Summary ___

Mechatronics Engineer with experience in design and improvement of automated processes, innovation of equipment and production systems using computer-aided design software to develop and test potential solutions. Proven skills in CAD/CAM/CAE, mechatronic design, PLC, embedded systems, programming, design of machine elements, integrated manufacturing systems. Additionally, he spends his free time in the research of trending and emergent technologies and its future applications in the country.

At the present time, he is actively looking forward to expand his knowledge, improve his skills and obtain experience related to the development of industrial solutions with a local and global focus.

Projects_

Designio

SYDERLABS

• Improve your design!

Quito, Ecuador April 2018 - Current

Syder IdeasQuito, Ecuador.SYDERLABSApril 2018 - Current

• Store your ideas!

Experience _____

Web DeveloperQuito, EcuadorINDEPENDENTApril 2018 - Current

- Redesign of Asociacion Ecuatoriana de Franquicias website.
- Redesign of Ecuafranquicias website.
- Redesign of Villagran Lara Asociados website.

Project ManagerQuito, Ecuador.ECUAFRANQUICIASJune 2017 - April 2019

- Franchisable business's operative and administrative processes documentation and management.
- Part-time job based-on time availability.

Research and Teaching Assistant of: Computer-aided Design, Manufacture and Engineering subject (CAD, CAM, CAE)

Quito, Ecuador

DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY AND MECHANIC SCIENCES - ESPE

Nov. 2015 - Mar. 2016

- Modelling, analysis and manufacture of a vehicle-based RIN.
- Out-come report generation, elaboration of processes sheets, G-code programming, design of the vehicle-based RIN using computer-aided software, strain simulation and post-process of the manufacturing operations.

GUIDO SANTILLÁN · CURRICULUM VITAE

1

Undergraduate Researcher, Manufacturing Processes Lab.

ARMY FORCES UNIVERSITY - ESPE

Quito, Ecuador.

Jan. 2015 - Mar. 2015

• Design and development mechanism for mobile robots mechanisms using 3D printing and laser cutting techniques.

Education

International Exchange Student

Brandenburg an der Havel, Germany

March - Sept. 2016

TECHNISCHE HOCHSCHULE BRANDENBURG

- Development of thesis project: "Implementation of HIL/SIL simulation techniques for real-time tests of vehicle models using the DSPACE platform"
- GPA: A-
- System modelling | Vehicle dynamics | Embedded systems

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), in Mechatronics Engineering

Quito, Ecuador

Apr. 2011 - Feb. 2016

ARMY FORCES UNIVERSITY - ESPE

- GPA: 17.43/20
- Industrial Robotics | Mechatronic Automation | CAD/CAM/CAE

Skills

LANGUAGES:

Spanish Native

English Fluent - Sufficiency in English Certificate completed at ESPE

German Basic - A1 completed at Technische Hochschule Brandenburg - Germany

PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE:

Web development HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bulma, Javascript, GIT, Webpack, TypeScript

Frontend React, Redux, React-Router, Next.js, Apollo, Gatsby, Progressive Web Apps

Backend NodeJS, Express, GraphOL, Docker, Web Sockets

Testing Jest, Enzyme

Databases PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis

Dev Ops AWS Lambda, Circle CI

Hosting Netlify, Heroku

Networking HTTP server with Apache, DNS, DHCP using Ubuntu Server

CMS Wordpress **Mobile** React Native **Desktop** Electron

Development Python, C, C++, Java, Assembler (micro-controller level)

Industrial-based LADDER Programming, G code

Others MT_FX

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE:

CAD/CAM/CAE Solidworks, AutoCAD 2D/3D, Siemens NX

Mathematical Analysis Matlab/Simulink, LabVIEW

Software Development Arduino, Processing **Electronic Design** Proteus, Multisim

Automation Wonderware InTouch, RSLogix, MicroWin Step7, FESTO Fluidsim, Automation Studio

Office Automation Microsoft Office, Project, Visio

Media Adobe Indesign, Adobe Illustrator, Sony Vegas

Operating Systems Windows, GNU Linux distributions (Ubuntu, Linux Mint)

Honors & Awards

2016	Honorable Mention, Awarded by the Army Forces University's principal	Quito, Ecuador
2016	Winner, EXPOINDUSTRIAL 2016 Mechatronics Competition – FESTO CHALLENGE	Quito, Ecuador
2016	High Performance Scholarship , Awarded by the <i>Army Forces University</i> to develop	Quito, Ecuador
	research projects in Germany	